Guide to the Miles & Edwards and Charles Hindley & Sons Correspondence
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
Miles & Edwards and Charles Hindley & Sons correspondence
1832-1875
MSS 4
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
1
2 boxes
Collection of letters from notable clients sent to the London interior decoration firm Miles & Edwards and its successor, Charles Hindley & Sons, from 1832 to 1875.
Miles & Edwards (London)
Charles Hindley & Sons (London)
Biographical / Historical
The firm of Miles & Edwards began operation in 1822 at 134 Oxford Street, Westminster, London. It specialized in fabric for curtains and furniture, as well as linings, fringes, cords and other fabric notions. They also sold carpets and wallpaper, made curtain rods and draperies to order, and took in furniture to be upholstered. While most of their clientele was in London, they took orders from across the British Isles. Customers in Ireland, Scotland, Wales and the Isle of Wight requested fabric samples and wrote letters with their orders. Though best known for its middle class clientele*, Miles & Edwards attracted customers from the highest levels of society, such as the Duchesses of Bedford and Marlborough.
Charles Hindley & Sons bought out Miles & Edwards in 1844, moving into their Oxford Street premises. Under the new management, the company continued to offer a similar line of products and services, with the addition of furniture sales. Charles Hindley & Sons operated until 1892.
*For information on the clientele of Miles & Edwards and Charles Hindley & Sons, see: Microulis, Laura. "Charles Hindley & Sons, London house furnishers of the nineteenth century: a paradigm of the middle-range market." Studies in the Decorative Arts, v. 5 (Spring/Summer 1998) p. 69-96.
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises business correspondence sent by clients to the Miles & Edwards company and its successor, Charles Hindley & Sons. The bulk of the letters date from either the 1830s-1840s or the 1870s, with a few scattered letters from the decades in between. The authors of the letters were overwhelmingly female, eighty percent being written by or on behalf of women. The unknown collector of the letters evidently chose to include them based on the importance of the author. The authors include many countesses, marchionesses, earls and barons, as well as several duchesses, a maid-of-honor to the Queen, and an archbishop. Many of the women were daughters of earls or barons who had married men of the same rank. Authors of both sexes ranked as baronets or higher, or occupied important posts in the clergy or military.
Some time after the collector gathered the letters (perhaps around 1880), he or she mounted them on card stock and made handwritten notes about each of the authors. In most cases, the notes include the author's first name, parentage, and marriage names and dates. The unknown annotator seems to have been interested in exploring the family ties and social position of each of the authors. Because he or she was working many years after most of the letters were written, this interest must not have been directly linked to business concerns. The purpose of the notations is not clear, though one might speculate that the annotator was simply interested in finding out more about the firm's former clientele, or perhaps was an amateur genealogist.
Because the collector separated these letters from a larger group of correspondence, they cannot be used as a comprehensive source for the business history of Miles & Edwards or Charles Hindley & Sons. However, they do contain valuable information on what sorts and quantities of fabric notable English women ordered for their households in the nineteenth century. A large proportion of the letters that specifically mention fabric types include references to chintz, showing the wide popularity of this material. Several mention particular designs such as stripes or small patterns. A noteworthy example is that of Lady Grace Gore, who requested fabric samples patterned with wild hops, strawberry leaves, lilac larkspur, and shamrocks (Box 1, folder 69). Others discuss colors such as pink, green, orange or blue. The size of the orders is often quite large: several involve quantities of 20 yards of fabric or more, while one on behalf of the Countess Robilant in Turin was for 372 yards (Box 1, folder 3).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by letter writer's name.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Each letter has been pasted to a piece of card stock, occasionally obscuring an address or other notes on the verso.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired April 2005, Paul Mellon Fund.
Bibliography
Microulis, Laura. "Charles Hindley &; Sons, London house furnishers of the nineteenth century: a paradigm of the middle-range market." Studies in the Decorative Arts, v. 5 (Spring/Summer 1998) p. 69-96.
Microulis, Laura. "The furniture drawings of Charles Hindley & Sons, 134 Oxford Street, London." Furniture History, v. 37 (2001) p. 67-90.
Carpets -- Great Britain; Chintz -- Great Britain; Decoration and ornament -- Great Britain; Draperies -- Great Britain; Furniture -- Great Britain; Interior decoration -- Great Britain; Merchants -- Great Britain -- Correspondence; Textile fabrics -- Great Britain; Upholstery -- Great Britain; Great Britain -- Social life and customs; Letters; Charles Hindley & Sons (London); Miles & Edwards (London)
- Letter: The Priory, Stanmore, Middlesex (?)., 1841 March; Abercorn, James Hamilton, Duke of, 1811-1885 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Requesting an estimate on altering silk curtains; ordering chintz curtains.
- Letter: The Priory, Stanmore, Middlesex (?)., 1841 April 13; Abercorn, Louisa Jane Russell, Marchioness of, 1812-1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Ordering paper, Scotch carpet and chintz curtains.
- Letter: Turin, Italy., 1846 May 23; Abercromby, Mary Elizabeth, lady, 1815?-1874 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Ordering, on behalf of the Countess Robilant in Turin, 372 yards of red striped chintz.
- Letter., 1841 June 3; Anstruther, Charlotte Lucy, Lady, 1806?-1890 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Returning paper patterns and requesting the company not to send anything more, as she did not like them.
- Letter: Enniscorthy, Ireland., 1852 September 25; Arran, Elizabeth Marianne Gore, Countess of, d. 1899 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Regarding payment of a bill.
- Letter: Southwood House (Isle of Thanet, East Kent?)., 1842 November 4; Ashburnham, Charlotte, Countess of, 1776-1862 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Requesting chintz patterns to make 2 sets of curtains and cover a couch bed, and for lining patterns, and for 2 pieces of Swiss muslin.
- Letter: Dublin, Ireland., 1874 August 11; Ashford, Olivia Charlotte Guinness, Baroness Ardilaun of, 1850-1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Regarding delivery of carpets; inquiry about price of a large piece of [chatting?] to use as a floor covering.
- Letter: 21 Berkeley Square, London., Undated; Balcarres, Maria Margaret Frances Lindsay, Countess of, d. 1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter: British Hotel., 1843 September 21; Bantry, Richard White, Earl of, 1800-1868 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Regarding delivery of an order, including 15 yards of drapery fringe; also a request for "patterns of chintz furniture."
- Letter: Busbey (?) House, Teddington., 1838 September 3; Barrington, Charlotte, Lady, d. 1858 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Regarding delivery of fabric [?] for a chair.
- Letter: Campden Hill, London., 1841 May 31; Bate, Maria, Marchioness of (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Requesting color-fast chintz patterns for drawing room furniture.
- Letter: Woburn Abbey., 1838 July; Bedford, Georgiana Russell, Duchess of, 1781-1853 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Requesting a washing table to be covered in marble.
- Letter: Wolverstone past Ipswich., [Unidentified year] May 15; Berners, Archdeacon (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Ordering muslin for 3 sets of curtains.
- Letter: 36 Wilton Crescent, London., 1844 April 24; Bishop, Lady (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Ordering 5 yards of chintz to match her furniture.
- Letter: Erskine, Glasgow, Scotland., 1845 January 9; Blantyre, Charles Stuart, Lord, 1818-1900 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Requesting pattern of fern-print chintz.
- Letter: Taymouth., 1852 June 30; Breadalbane, Elizabeth Campbell, Marchioness of, 1803-1861 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Ordering wood curtain rings and poles, and chintz to cover several chairs.
- Letter., 1843; Bridport, Samuel Hood, Baron, b. 1788 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Confirming payment of £200.
- Letter: Broke Hall, Suffolk., 1844 February 17; Broke, Philip, Sir, 1804-1855 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Returning patterns of marble paper and green baize; requesting 3 more pieces of paper; requesting bill.
- Letter: Compton Corner., [Circa 1840] Apr 19; Brooke, Julia Henrietta Anson, Lady, d.1886 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Requesting estimate for a drawing room table and a Scotch striped cloth.
- Letter., Undated; Bruce, Lady (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Regarding the time when a house will be vacant.
- Letter: Inchcomb (?)., 1841 March 29; Buckinghamshire, Anne Glover, Countess of (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Requesting covers for furniture to be made ready.
- Letter: London., 1874 January 10; Byles, John Barnard, Sir (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Letter: 21 Eaton Place, London., 1838 February 5; Byron, Elizabeth Mary, Lady, d.1873 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Ordering a dark orange cover for a table.
- Letter: Putney Heath, London., 1846 June 19; Cadogan, Henry Charles, Earl of, 1812-1873 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Returning chintz patterns and requesting description of a "folio holder."
- Letter: Tittenhanger (?)., 1847 November 6; Caledon, Jane-Frederica Alexander, Lady (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Letter: Evely (?)., 1841 July 6; Carr, Lady (wife of Bishop Robert James Carr of Worcester) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Returning a table cover that she did not like.
- Letter: Bath., 1840 April 10; Carrington, Charlotte Augusta Annabella Smith, Lady (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Returning chintz patterns.
- Letter: Holly Hill, Southampton., Undated; Cholmondeley, Henry Vere, Lord, 1834-1882 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Returning a paper pattern and requesting 4 more pieces.
- Letter: Carlton St., London., 1841 July 27; Cholmondeley, Susan Somerset, Marchioness of, 1804-1886 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Requesting that a piece cloth be mounted [?] as an ottoman stool.
- Letter: 32 Belgrave Square, London., 1838 July; Clanwilliam, Elizabeth Meade, Countess of, circa 1809-1858 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Requesting that a person be sent to take measurements for rods for hanging pictures.
- Letter., Undated; Clare, Elizabeth Julia Georgiana Fitzgibbon, Countess of, 1793-1879 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Requesting receipt for a chair [?].
- Letter: Straffan, Colbridge., 1843 October 14; Clarina, Susan Elizabeth Massey, Lady (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Letter: Bowood, Calne., 1843 February 3; Cole, Mary, Lady (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Sending payment and requesting receipt.
- Letter: Abington House, Abington., [Circa 1860] November 11; Colebrooke, Elizabeth Margaret, Lady (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Ordering another set of blue ribbon and flower [illegible], and requesting her cleaned chintzes be sent.
- Letter: Namptwich., 1848 December 14; Combermere, Mary Woolley Cotton, Viscountess (Box 1, Folder 35)
  of, ca. 1799-1889. Complaining that the company did not inform her of a delay.
- Letter., 1844; Conroy, Alicia Parsons, Lady (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Returning a pattern of chintz.
- Letter., 1871 April 11; Courtenay, C., Lady (Box 1, Folder 37)
  [Illegible request.]
- Letter: Combe (?) Abbey., [Before 1860]; Craven, Louisa, Countess of, circa 1782-1860 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Disputing a bill.
- Letter., 1843 February 11; Croft, Anne Knox, Lady (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Asking Mr. Edward to call on her.
- Letter., 1844 July 2; Crompton, Lady (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Requesting calico lining pattern, and confirming order of 60 yards of chintz.
- Letter: Chevening, Kent., 1852; Dalmeny, Catherine Lucy Wilhelmina Primrose, Lady, 1819-1901. (Later Duchess of Cleveland.) (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Ordering 45 yards of bright green fabric.
- Letter: Kirtlington Park, Oxford., [Unidentified year] January 26; Dashwood, Sophia, Lady, d. 1894 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Returning lined curtain pattern and requesting 3 pieces of fabric.
- Letter: Lucen's? Park, Brighton., 1846 August 15; Denbigh, Rudolph William Basil Feilding, Earl of, 1823-1892 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Ordering 1 piece of tabinet and 1 piece of chintz "for covers."
- Letter: Kilkenny (?), Ireland., 1843 October 2; Desart, John Otway O'Conner Cuffe, Earl of, 1818-1865 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Returning chintz pattern; ordering 90 yards of it with lining and binding.
- Letter: 4 Bryanstone Court (?), London., 1838; Devon, Elizabeth Fortescue Courtenay, Countess of, 1801-1867 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Requesting sketches of several "different shapes in the style of the age of Louis quatorze."
- Letter: 52 S. [illegible] Street., 1874 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Requesting a person to come [... illegible].
- Letter: 21 Belgrave Square, London., 1843 April 12; Ducie, Elizabeth Moreton, Countess of, d. 1865 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Requesting several patterns of chintz.
- Letter: Witley Court, Stourport., 1827 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Ordering additional chintz from a previous request, to make chair covers, curtains, and door portieres.
- Letter: [Ken?]sington., 1839 July 9; Dufferin, Anne Dorothea, Lady (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Letter: 30 Lowndes St., London, 1844 March; Effingham, Charlotte Howard, Countess of, circa 1776-1864 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Ordering 3 yards of cotton print fabric, and requesting bill for an ottoman stool.
- Letter: Batchford (?)., 1843 April 13; Egerton, J., Lady (Box 1, Folder 51)
  Ordering 2 pieces of chintz.
- Letter: Hamilton Place, London., 1844 February 20; Eldon, Louisa Duncombe Scott, Countess of, 1826-1852 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Ordering hair for a hair-pillow; requesting a key for a drawer she had put in a table; and requesting repairs on several other drawers.
- Letter: 48 Charter Sq., London., 1854 June 1; Ely, Anna Maria Loftus, Marchioness of, circa 1790-1857 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Regarding payment of a bill [?].
- Letter., 1838 August 30; Essex, George Capel-Coningsby, Earl of, 1757-1839 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  Ordering 40 yards of linen.
- Letter: Farnham., 1843 October 7; Farnham, Anna Frances Esther Maxwell, Lady, d. 1868 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  Complaining of faulty workmanship on a chintz sofa cover, and requesting another order of chintz to replace it.
- Letter: Farnham., 1844 January 13; Farnham, Henry Maxwell, Baron, 1799-1868 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Sending a payment of £204.
- Letter: Larkwith (?) Street, London., 1843 October; Feilding, Elizabeth, Lady (Box 1, Folder 57)
  Requesting 2 carpets to be installed.
- Letter: Bure Homage, near Christchurch...., 1838 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  Confirming receipt of curtains and requesting bill.
- Letter: Delgaty Castle, Aberdeenshire, Scotland., 1840 July 13; Fife, Agnes Georgiana Elizabeth Duff, Countess of, 1829-1869 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  Regarding a delivery.
- Letter: 15 Halkin Street West, London., 1843 March; FitzHardinge of Bristol, Charlotte Berkeley, Lady, 1806-1881 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  Ordering a covering for a chair; describing details of how she would like it decorated.
- Letter: Connaught Place, London., 1843 January 21; Fitzwygram, Selina, Lady (Box 1, Folder 61)
  Complaining that the bed and window curtains she ordered have taken too long to be prepared; Explaining that the company must now keep them until she returns to London next year.
- Letter., 1838 July; Flahault-de-la-Billardrie, Margaret Nairne Flahault, Countess of, 1788-1867 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  Sending a carpet sample for matching to her silk curtains.
- Letter: Near Kincardine, Scotland., 1838 August 15; Flahault-de-la-Billardrie, Margaret Nairne Flahault, Countess of, 1788-1867 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  Ordering 4.5 yards of blue [illegible] and at least 10 yards of Chinese pattern crimson silk; inquiring about green satin.
- Letter: Stoke Edith Park, Hereford., 1874 April 20; Foley, Emily, Lady, d. 1900 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  Requesting Venetian carpet patterns "for the back stairs."
- Letter: Castle Hill, Devon., 1868; Fortescue, Countess (Box 1, Folder 65)
  Complaining that not enough made-to-order chintz was delivered; requesting more if it is ready-made, or alternative patterns if it is not.
- Letter: 4 Seamon (?) Place, Park Lane, London., 1873 May 24; Franklin, Jane Griffin, Lady (Box 1, Folder 66)
  Regarding a furniture delivery.
- Letter., 1842 November 28; Getland?, Sophia Jane, Countess (Box 1, Folder 67)
  Regarding delivery of silk damask and screens [?].
- Letter: Niton, Isle of Wight., 1841 April 23; Gordon, Julia, Lady (Box 1, Folder 68)
  Regarding delivery of chairs.
- Letter: 28 Brunswick Square, Brighton., 1844 January 26; Gore, Grace, Lady (Box 1, Folder 69)
  Requesting pieces of fabric patterned with wild hops, strawberry leaves, lilac larkspur, and shamrocks; inquiring about paper she ordered; inquiring about price of a bed [cover?].
- Letter: Fowler's, Hawkhurst, Kent., [Unidentified year] February 23; Grant, Lady (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Letter: Wrest Park, Silsoe., 1841 January 26; Grey, Henrietta Frances Robinson, Countess de, d. 1845 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  Requesting "strong & cheap" cotton and chintz patterns for covering chairs in servants' rooms.
- Letter: Melville Carth (?)., 1848 September 14; Haddington, Thomas Hamilton, Earl of, 1780-1858 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  Regarding an insurance payment.
- Letter., 1843 July 17; Hamond, Graham Eden, Sir, 1779-1862 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Letter: Stapleford Park, Melton Mowbray., 1844 January; Harborough, Robert Sherard, Earl of, 1797-1859 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  Regarding delivery of a flower stand.
- Letter: Bishopthorpe, York., 1838 August 31; Harcourt, Edward, 1757-1847 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  Reporting that the pieces of chintz he received did not match the fabric he already had, but that he will use it anyway to cover the backs of some furniture.
- Letter., 1873 July 2; Harcourt, Edward William (Box 2, Folder 76)
  Reporting that Lady Susan did not like the pattern she was sent.
- Letter., 1844; Hardwicke, Charles Philip Yorke, Earl of, 1799-1873 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  [Short illegible note.]
- Letter., [Circa 1844?]; Hardwicke, Elizabeth Yorke, Countess, d. 1858 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  Ordering paper, and remarking on its pink color.
- Letter., 1838; Hardwicke, Susan Yorke, Countess of (Box 2, Folder 79)
  1810-1886. Requesting that the company hold some items for her for a few hours while she arranges delivery; regarding delivery of furniture.
- Letter., 1874 August 17; Hatherton, Edward Richard Littleton, Baron, 1815-1888 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  Ordering a mahogany dumbwaiter and 2 trays.
- Letter., 1852 May 19; Headfort, Thomas Taylour, Marquess of, 1787-1870 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  Regarding repayment of money he had loaned the company.
- Letter., 1844 February 22; Henley, Hariett, Lady (wife of Robert Henley, 2nd baron) (Box 2, Folder 82)
  Inquiring whether a hatchment could be altered to include Lord Henley's arms, and requesting the price.
- Letter., 1872 September 25; Henley, Lady. (wife of Anthony, 3rd Bart.) (Box 2, Folder 84)
  Ordering 2 folding chairs; regarding delivery of a cabinet.
- Letter., Undated; Hervey-Bathurst, Clare Emily, Lady, d. 1867 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  Delivery of baskets [?] to be lined with muslin; and request for "Chinese pattern chintz" to cover an ottoman.
- Letter., 1873 February 28; Heytesbury, William Henry Ashe A'Court, Baron, 1809-1891 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  Regarding possible order of a table.
- Letter., 1838 July 21; Higgins, Samuel G., Sir (Box 2, Folder 87)
  Requesting Mr. Miles or Mr. Edwards to call on him.
- Letter., 1843 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  Ordering 50 yards of fabric; requesting pink color-fast patterns, and red-striped patterns for a bedroom sofa.
- Letter., 18[51?] October 28; Home, Cospatrick Alexander Douglas-Home, Earl of, 1799-1881 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  Ordering an additional 24 yards of blue fringe and 2 [lapels?].
- Letter., 1871 February 7; Home, Lucy Elizabeth Douglas-Home, Countess of, 1805-1887 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  Ordering 97 yards of linen.
- Letter., 1843 July; Honywood, Mary, Lady, d. 1849 (Box 2, Folder 91)
- Letter., 1843 August 2; Hume-Campbell, Juliana Rebecca, Lady (Box 2, Folder 92)
  Requesting chintz patterns.
- Letter., [1842?] December 2; Jersey, Margaret Elizabeth Child Villiers, Countess of, 1849-1945 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  Scheduling a meeting.
- Letter., 1843 May; Johnston, Maria, Lady (Box 2, Folder 94)
  Regarding the details of how her bonnet baskets are to be lined with pink calico.
- Letter., 1841 August 19; Keats, Lady (Box 2, Folder 95)
  Regarding the sending of furniture from her drawing room.
- Letter: Killarney, Ireland., 1846 July 15; Kenmare, Augusta Anne, Countess of (Box 2, Folder 96)
  Ordering 18 additional hangers [for curtains?].
- Letter., 1843 July 21; Kerry, Lady (Box 2, Folder 97)
  Ordering a table.
- Letter: Bournemouth., [After 1851] May 15; Kintore, Louisa Madeline, Countess of (Box 2, Folder 98)
  Reporting that the last silk pattern she received was too light; requesting another pattern to match a piece of dark velvet.
- Letter: Sarsden., 1844 June; Langston, Julia, Lady, d. 1863 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  Ordering a red Persian-stripe patent felt table cloth.
- Letter., 1841 July; Lansdowne, Henry Petty-FitzMaurice, Marquess of, 1816-1866 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  Regarding a bill.
- Letter: Bowood., [Before 1851]; Lansdowne, Louisa Emma Petty-FitzMaurice, Marchioness of, 1785-1851 (Box 2, Folder 102)
- Letter., 1838 July 1; Lennox, Mary Margaret, Lady (Box 2, Folder 103)
- Letter., 1874 March 9; Lethbridge, C., esq. Washford (Box 2, Folder 104)
  Declining an invitation.
- Letter., 1838 June 1; Lethbridge, Julia, Lady, d. 1855 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  Inquiring about the price of a chintz pattern.
- Letter: Wynyard?, 1841 July 4; Londonderry, Charles William Vane, Marquess, 1778-1854 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  Ordering 19 more pieces of [illegible] gold paper.
- Letter: Barley Thorpe, Oakham, Rutland., [Unidentified year] January 2; Lonsdale, Countess of (Box 2, Folder 107)
  Reporting that she will be away for several days.
- Letter., 1873 February 19; Lovell, Francis Frederick. Badminton, Chippenham (Box 2, Folder 108)
- Letter: London (?)., 1844 March; Lowther, Lucy Eleanor, Lady, d. 1848 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  Requesting a meeting.
- Letter: Shrewsbury (?)., [Unidentified year] August 31; Lyster, Charlotte Barbara, Lady (Box 2, Folder 110)
  Ordering 24 yards of fabric, tacks with small gilt heads.
- Letter: London (?)., 1841 March 19; Manners, Jane, Lady, d. 1846 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  Ordering curtains to be made.
- Letter: Blenheim., 1843 January 17; Marlborough, Jane Spencer-Churchill, Duchess of, 1798-1844 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  Ordering chintz, a bed with straight cornices, bed curtains lined with green glazed calico, four window curtains that can be drawn side-to-side (not the old fashioned way of drawing up), and a plain valance with a fringe, all to furnish the Duke's bedroom.
- Letter: Godalming., 1852 June 11; Meath, Melosina Adelaide Brabazon, Countess of, circa 1781-1844 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  Ordering 20 yards of modern pattern chintz.
- Letter: London (?)., 1832 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  Ordering linen curtains to be made with two breadths of fabric, rather than one, as they look "rather plain & scanty."
- Letter., 1844 November 22; Middleton, Jane, Lady (Box 2, Folder 115)
  Requesting a piece of light glazed calico, or twilled if the glazed is not available.
- Letter., 1871 July; Middleton, Lady Brumstead (Box 2, Folder 116)
  [Illegible note, regarding an order that was not received or incorrect.]